Database Scene one, take one.
قاعدة البيانات، المشهد الأول، اللقطة الأولى.
Here is a bar chart providing the likely places you lost your remote control.
هنا مخطط شريطي يعرض لكم الأماكن المحتملة التي تفقدوا فيها جهاز التحكم عن بُعد.
You can see that the most likely place you will find the remote,
يمكننا أن نلاحظ أن المكان الأكثر احتمالًا لتجد فيه جهاز التحكم عن بعد،
is actually in your hand.
هو في يدكم في الواقع.
While the least likely is that it's gone forever and you'll never find it.
بينما الاحتمال الأقل هو إنه اختفى للأبد ولن تجده أبدًا.
Other options for where your remote might be,
هناك خيارات أخرى للأماكن التي ستجدون فيها جهازكم
are shown here in descending order.
معروضة هنا بترتيب تنازلي.
Let's try again. Database scene one take two.
دعونا نجرب ذلك. قاعدة البيانات، المشهد الأول، اللقطة الثانية.
Have you ever been looking for a hat and find out that you're already wearing it?
هل سبق لك يوما ما أن بحثت عن قبعة واكتشفت أنك ترتديها بالفعل؟
Or looking for your keys and find out they're in your back pocket?
أو بحثت عن مفاتيحك واكتشفت أنها في جيبك الخلفي؟
Or looking for your backpack and you find out that it's on your back?
أو بحثت عن حقيبة ظهرك واكتشفت أنها على ظهرك بالفعل؟
Turns out losing your remote is the same problem.
يتضح من ذلك أن فقدانك لجهاز التحكم عن بعد هو نفس المشكلة.
This chart highlights the seven places your remote is likely to be.
هذا المخطط يسلط الضوء على سبعة أماكن من المحتمل أن يوجد فيها جهاز التحكم عن بعد
The top place, is in your hand.
المكان الأول، في يدكم.
The least likely place that it is, is lost forever.
المكان الأقل احتمالًا، هو أنكم فقدتموه للأبد.
But before you think you were one of those two people,
ولكن قبل أن تعتقدوا أنكم واحد من هذين الشخصين،
make sure you check under the couch,
تأكد من أنكم بحثتم تحت الأريكة،
next to the TV, in the fridge,
أو بجانب التلفزيون وفي الثلاجة
in your shirt pocket and under the rug.
وفي جيب القميص وتحت السجادة.
Before you blame the dog for eating your remote,
قبل أن تلوم كلبك على أكل جهاز التحكم عن بعد،
or think an alien came from space and stole your remote, check your hand.
أو تعتقد أن كائن من الفضاء جاء وسرق جهازك، تحقق من يدك.
It's unlikely your remote is gone forever.
من المستبعد أن يختفي جهاز التحكم عن بعد للأبد.